## Nick Seah

Industrial Engineer/Data Scientist

#### Contact

Address

Phoenix, AZ 85042

**Phone** 

5712964490

E-mail

nickseah1@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com

/in/nickseah/

www

https://github.com/nickseah1

## Skills

Python

SQL

Machine Learning

**MATLAB** 

Tableau

Dash

Any Logic Simulation

**Javascript** 

Production Control

GitHub

**PowerBI** 

Materials Resource Planning

Project Management

Altervx

Root Cause Analysis

Snowflake

SOP Creating/Implementation

JDA Supply Chain Planning

WMS

SAP

MS Access

MS Project

Spark

Industrial Engineer with 3+ Years of experience. Spearheaded a continuous improvement program using PowerBI, SQL, Python, and lean six sigma principles resulting in a 55% decrease in safety incidents, a 10% improvement in Absolute Piece Accuracy, and 99.5 % on-time delivery.

### Education

2021-01 -2022-12 Ph.D.: Data Science, Engineering And Analytics (Partial)

Arizona State University - Tempe, AZ

GPA: 3.8

Courses Completed: Statistical Data Mining, Design of Experiments, Data Visualization, Stochastic Operations

Research, Data Science for System Informatics

2016-08 -20202 Bachelor of Science: Industrial Engineering

Arizona State University - Tempe, AZ

3.2 GPA

## **Personal Projects**

## Machine Learning Interactive Web Application

Self Employed Web

 Developed a Python based application to predict NBA All-Stars (97% Accuracy).

## **Work History**

2022-02 -Current

## **Supply Chain Analyst**

Leslie's Pool Supply, Phoenix, United States

- Built a comprehensive PowerBI suite of reports to visualize, track and monitor supply chain KPIs.
- Developed a python script to automate store delivery notifications reducing time spent by 75%.
- Led the transition of supply chain reporting into Snowflake by identifying data sources and establishing standardized and efficient processes to reduce waste from supply chain reporting.

## 2021-08 -2021-12

# Information Systems Engineering Teaching Assistant

Arizona State University

Taught SQL and relational database design to a class 100+ Industrial Engineering undergraduate students.

2021-05 -

### **Graduate Student Researcher**

2021-08

Intel/Arizona State University

 Developed a Digital Twin simulation using AnyLogic, Python, and Javascript to run experiments to maximize throughput and run what-if scenarios.

2020-05 -2021-05

#### **Graduate Student Researcher**

National Science Foundation/Arizona State University

 Developed a multi-population COVID-19 simulation model to guide intervention efforts in Arizona

#### Certifications

Machine Learning Fundamentals - Dataquest Lean Six Sigma Green Belt - Arizona State University